Guide to the Ivan Collins Papers 1903-1971
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
- Museums and exhibitions, 1946-1971; Series IV:; 1.5 cubic feet.
  - Oregon Historical Society, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 9/2)
    2 pamphlets, note, business card, 32 letters, seminar schedule, OHS information sheet
  - Museums (Fixtures, etc.), undated (Box-folder 9/3)
    Magazine, newspaper item, 3 magazine items
  - Museums, General, 1953-1969 (Box-folder 9/4)
    Notes, postcard, 2 magazine items, 3 newspaper items, 10 pamphlets, 24 letters
  - Amon Carter Museum of Western Art, undated (Box-folder 9/5)
  - Douglas Co. Museum, 1970 (Box-folder 9/6)
    Postcard, letter
  - California Beaches and Parks, undated (Box-folder 9/7)
    3 pamphlets, brochure, magazine item, Dufur pioneer meeting notice
  - California Parks Brochures (Dup), undated (Box-folder 9/8)
    Postcard, notes, 19 brochures
  - Jacksonville Museum, 1967 (Box-folder 9/9)
    6 letters, note
  - Klamath County Museum, undated (Box-folder 9/10)
    Pamphlet, letter
  - Jung Museum, undated (Box-folder 9/11)
    Inventory, 3 pamphlets, 3 newspaper items, acquisition form, Wesley Jung biographical data
  - Lane County Historian, undated (Box-folder 9/12)
    Pamphlet, journal, essay, general Collins information
  - Maritime Museum, 1953-1969 (Box-folder 9/13)
    2 newspaper items, 3 newsletters, 10 letters
  - New York State Historical Association, undated (Box-folder 9/14)
    Cooperstown seminar guide
  - Oakland Museum, undated (Box-folder 9/15)
    Magazine item
  - Oregon Historical Society—Historical Properties Committee, 1970 (Box-folder 9/16)
    Stationery (Lane County Historical Society), envelope, 9 newspaper items, 4 letters, 2 survey forms, committee minutes, "visual appraisal", report, agenda, urban design study
  - Portland Art Museum, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 9/17)
    Journal, museum guide, 8 letters
  - Department of Interior, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 9/18)
    9 letters, notes
  - San Mateo Historical Museum, 1969 (Box-folder 9/19)
    Letter
  - St. Louis Westward Expansion Museum, undated (Box-folder 9/20)
  - Shelburne Museum, 1969 (Box-folder 9/21)
    Pamphlet, catalog, inventory, 3 letters, label, advertisement
  - [Construction History], undated (Box-folder 9/22)
    Bound volume including loose sheet with graph of construction and some business cards
  - [Book], undated (Box-folder 9/23)
    Text for Collins' book, Horse Power Days
- Research and Clippings, ca. 1965-1970; Series V:; 1.5 cubic feet.
  Notebooks containing contact addresses, record of wagon constructions, sketches and notes. Index cards, arranged alphabetically, with wagon details and specifications.
  - Scrapbook, undated (Box-folder 10/1)
    Contents of scrapbook
  - Addresses—Wagon Notes, undated (Box-folder 10/2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 10/3)
    2 photographs, 3 letters, sketches of display details, 3 page narrative, store scrip, 2 magazine articles, 2 exhibit description cards
  - Exhibit description cards, undated
    - Covered Wagon & Buckboard, undated (Box-folder 10/4)
      See also oversize 2012-6, boxes 12 & 13, and box 1 folder 11
    - U.S. Army Escort Wagon, undated (Box-folder 10/5)
      See also oversize 2012-53, boxes 12 & 3, and box 2 folder 1
    - Tank Wagon, undated (Box-folder 10/6)
      See also oversize 2012-47, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folder 27
    - Header Box, undated (Box-folder 10/7)
    - Bobsled, undated (Box-folder 10/8)
      See also oversize 2012-46, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folder 21
    - Orchard Wagon, undated (Box-folder 10/9)
    - Cutter, undated (Box-folder 10/10)
      See also oversize 2012-63, boxes 12 & 13, and box 3 folder 3
    - Express Wagon, undated (Box-folder 10/11)
      See also oversize 2012-20, boxes 12 & 13, and box 3 folder 22
    - Gooseneck Dray, undated (Box-folder 10/12)
      See also oversize 2012-27, boxes 12 & 13, and box 1 folder 30
    - Governess Cart, undated (Box-folder 10/13)
      See also oversize 2012-28, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folder 4
    - Logging Wagon, undated (Box-folder 10/14)
      See also oversize 2012-33, boxes 12 & 13, and box 3 folder 10
    - Fuel Wagon, undated (Box-folder 10/15)
      See also oversize 2012-23, boxes 12 & 13, and box 3 folder 18
    - Lumber Wagon, undated (Box-folder 10/16)
      See also oversize 2012-36, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folder 9
    - "Roll Off" Lumber Wagon, undated (Box-folder 10/17)
      See also oversize 2012-34, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folder 10
    - Wool Wagon, undated (Box-folder 10/18)
    - Rural Free Delivery Wagon, undated (Box-folder 10/19)
    - Canopy Top Surrey, undated (Box-folder 10/20)
      See also oversize 2012-41, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folders 26 & 36
    - Barouche (American Caleche), undated (Box-folder 10/21)
      See also oversize 2012-12, boxes 12 & 13, and box 1 folder 5
    - Conestoga, undated (Box-folder 10/22)
      See also oversize 2012-2, boxes 12 & 13, and box 1 folder 25
    - Red River Cart, undated (Box-folder 10/23)
      See also oversize 2012-39, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folder 18
    - Freight Wagon, undated (Box-folder 10/24)
      See also oversize 2012-22, boxes 12 & 13, and box 1 folder 16
    - Stick Wagon, undated (Box-folder 10/25)
      See also oversize 2012-15, boxes 12 & 13, and box 1 folder 2
    - Dump Wagon, undated (Box-folder 10/26)
      See also oversize 2012-13, boxes 12 & 13, and box 1 folder 32
    - Wheeled Scraper, undated (Box-folder 10/27)
      See also oversize 2012-43, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folder 29
    - Civil War Cannon, undated (Box-folder 10/28)
      See also oversize 2012-25, boxes 12 & 13, and box 1 folder 22
    - Balloon Gas Generator Wagons, undated (Box-folder 10/29)
      See also oversize 2012-9, boxes 12 & 13, and box 1 folder 4
    - Top Buggy, undated (Box-folder 10/30)
    - Road Coach, undated (Box-folder 10/31)
      See also oversize 2012-40 and boxes 12 & 13
    - Hearse, undated (Box-folder 10/32)
      See also oversize 2012-51, boxes 12 & 13, and box 3 folder 13
    - Farm Wagon, undated (Box-folder 10/33)
      See also oversize 2012-10 and boxes 12 & 13
    - Mud Wagon, undated (Box-folder 10/34)
    - Spring Sleigh, undated (Box-folder 11/1)
      See also oversize 2012-45, boxes 12 & 13, and box 3 folder 4
    - Colonial Sleigh, undated (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Hook & Ladder Truck, undated (Box-folder 11/3)
      See also oversize 2012-32, boxes 12 & 13, and box 3 folder 20
    - Hose Wagon, undated (Box-folder 11/4)
      See also oversize 2012-24, boxes 12 & 13, and box 3 folder 21
    - Sprinkler Wagon, undated (Box-folder 11/5)
      See also oversize 2012-42, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folders 24 & 30
    - Wagonette, undated (Box-folder 11/6)
      See also oversize 2012-48, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folders 28 & 33
    - Medicine Wagon, undated (Box-folder 11/7)
      See also oversize 2012-55, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folder 13
    - Salesman's Sample Wagon, undated (Box-folder 11/8)
      See also oversize 2012-16, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folder 28
    - Milk Wagon, undated (Box-folder 11/9)
      See also oversize 2012-35 and boxes 12 & 13
    - Meat Packer's Wagon, undated (Box-folder 11/10)
      See also oversize 2012-21 and boxes 12 & 13
    - Brewery Wagon, undated (Box-folder 11/11)
      See also oversize 2012-7, boxes 12 & 13, and box 1 folder 8
    - Ice Wagon, undated (Box-folder 11/12)
      See also oversize 2012-31, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folder 7
    - Physician's Phaeton, undated (Box-folder 11/13)
      See also oversize 2012-38, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folder 15
    - Break, undated (Box-folder 11/14)
      See also oversize 2012-11, boxes 12 & 13, and box 1 folder 9
    - Brooklyn Delivery Wagon, undated (Box-folder 11/15)
      See also oversize 2012-18 and boxes 12 & 13
    - Baggage & Transfer Truck, undated (Box-folder 11/16)
    - Grain Box, undated (Box-folder 11/17)
      See also oversize 2012-29, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folder 5
    - Sheep Camp Wagon, undated (Box-folder 11/18)
      See also oversize 2012-44, boxes 12 & 13, and box 3 folder 5
    - Concord Coach, undated (Box-folder 11/19)
      See also oversize 2012-1, boxes 12 & 13, and box 3 folder 1
    - National Park Coach, undated (Box-folder 11/20)
      See also oversize 2012-52, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folder 32
    - "C" or Eight-Spring Victoria, undated (Box-folder 11/21)
      See also oversize 2012-65, boxes 12 & 13, and box 1 folder 6
    - Rockaway, undated (Box-folder 11/22)
      See also oversize 2012-3, boxes 12 & 13, and box 2 folder 19
    - Hotel Bus, undated (Box-folder 11/23)
      See also oversize 2012-54, boxes 12 & 13, and box 3 folder 7
    - Brougham, undated (Box-folder 11/24)
      See also oversize 2012-8, boxes 12 & 13, and box 1 folder 10
    - Hansom Cab, undated (Box-folder 11/25)
      See also oversize 2012-30, boxes 12 & 13, and box 3 folder 15
  - Notebook, undated (Box-folder 11/26-11/27)
  - Telephone Address Book, undated (Box-folder 11/28)
  - Notebook, undated (Box-folder 11/29)
  - Log Book, undated (Box-folder 11/30)
  - Scrapbook, undated (Box-folder 11/31)
  - Wagon Specifications, undated. (Box-folder 12/1)
    Index cards.
  - Wagon Specifications, undated. (Box-folder 13/1)
- Reference copies of Collins's drawings, undated; Series VI:
  - Reference Reproductions., undated (Box-folder Oversize/66)
    2012-1 through 2012-8, 2012-9
  - Reference Reproductions., undated (Box-folder Oversize/67)
    2012-11 through 2012-20
  - Reference Reproductions., undated (Box-folder Oversize/68)
    2012-21 through 2012-30
  - Reference Reproductions., undated (Box-folder Oversize/69)
    2012-31 through 2012-40
  - Reference Reproductions., undated (Box-folder Oversize/70)
    2012-41 through 2012-50
  - Reference Reproductions., undated (Box-folder Oversize/71)
    2012-51 through 2012-55, 2012-65
  - Negatives, undated
    - Negative—2012-1., undated (Box-folder 14/1)
    - Negative—2012-2—1 of 2., undated (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Negative—2012-2—2 of 2., undated (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Negative—2012-6., undated (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Negative—2012-7., undated (Box-folder 14/5)
    - Negative—2012-8., undated (Box-folder 14/6)
    - Negative—2012-16., undated (Box-folder 14/7)
    - Negative—2012-21—1 of 2., undated (Box-folder 14/8)
    - Negative—2012-21—2 of 2., undated (Box-folder 14/9)
    - Negative—2012-27., undated (Box-folder 14/10)
    - Negative—2012-28., undated (Box-folder 14/11)
    - Negative—2012-32., undated (Box-folder 14/12)
    - Negative—2012-33., undated (Box-folder 14/13)
    - Negative—2012-36., undated (Box-folder 14/14)
    - Negative—2012-49., undated (Box-folder 14/15)
    - Negative—2012-50—1 of 2., undated (Box-folder 14/16)
    - Negative—2012-50—2 of 2., undated (Box-folder 14/17)
    - Negative—2012-55., undated (Box-folder 14/18)
    - Negatives. (Box-folder 15/1)
      2012-1(4), 3, 4, 5, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 17, 18, 19, 20, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26(2), 29, 30, 31, 34, 35, 37, 38, 39, 40, 41, 42, 43, 44, 45, 46, 47, 48, 51, 52, 53, 54, 65